He did it... down there...
他干在...在那下面...
This is Salamander. I want a security escort
to come to the interrogation room immediately. /38.9
我是 Salamander. 我要一个护卫小队立刻到审讯室来
I'm releasing two prisoners.
They are to be conducted to the main gates and set free. /45.0
我要释放两个囚犯．要把他们带到大门, 然后释放
Is that understood? Good.
明白了吗？好
- Well I hope that works.
- So do I.
- 好了我期望这能行  - 我也期望
What do you want us to do when we get outside?
等我们出去了, 你想让我们做什么？
There are plenty of public phones in the area.
Dial double zero one and ask for a man named Forrester.
在这个地区有很多公共电话．拨两个零, 找一个叫做 Forrester 的人
Eh?
嗯？
He's my deputy to this area.
他是我在这个区域的副官
Double zero one Forrester.
拨两个零找 Forrester
Tell him where I am and just say "redhead".
告诉他我在哪里, 只需要说＂红头＂
Redhead.
"红头"
Redhead. Is that clear?
"红头＂, 明白了吗？
Redhead? Is that your wife?
＂红头＂, 是你妻子吗？
It's our emergency call.
这是我们的紧急联络语
Sorry.
抱歉
Salamander... Is the, is the pass in order?.../?
Salamander ...那个, 通行证fixme...
Very well, you have my authority.
很好, 我已经授权了
What's all that about?
这都是什么情况？
We have a visitor.
我们有客人来访了
Giles Kent. What are you doing here?
Giles Kent, 你在这里做什么？
Oh, I've been looking forward to this meeting. /50.9
哦, 我一直期待着这次会面
You're getting careless.
You didn't double lock the doors./53.6
你大意了, 没有给门上双重锁
Oh, its all right, I've done it now. /56.0
哦, 没事的．我现在已经弄好了
The only way anybody can get through there
is to blast their way through.
谁想穿过它, 唯一的方法是炸开一条路
- How did you get into the Research Centre?
- Oh, you know me.
- 你怎么进入研究中心的？  - 噢, 你知道我的
There isn't a pass in the world I can't get my hands on
- if I put my mind to it.
这个世界上没有哪个通行证我搞不到手, 只要我想要
You won't find it so easy getting out.
你会发现想出去就没那么容易了
Really? Well we'll see.
真的吗？那我们回头看看
I'm not on my own this time.
I've got friends here with me. /15.1
我这次不是单独来的, 带了朋友来这里
And between us we're going to fix you once and for all.
而咱们俩这次就一劳永逸地解决你
You always were a tiresome man, Kent.
你一直都是一个令人讨厌的家伙, Kent
I'm going to be more than tiresome this time. /23.6
我这次打算比＂令人讨厌＂还要过分
You know the biggest mistake you ever made
was not killing me when you had the chance.
你知道你犯下的最大的错误就是, 你有机会的时候没有杀死我
Oh so you going to kill me huh? How petty.
What good do you think that will do?
哦, 看来你打算杀死我, 哈？很好．你觉得这会带来什么好处？
Hold it! Now don't move quickly,
my nerves are a bit shaky at the moment.
别动！现在不要做大动作, 这会儿我的神经可有点不太稳当
We must get in there somehow.
我们必须想法进去
We can't without the emergency key,
and Salamander has it in there.
没有紧急钥匙我们也没办法, Salamander 拿进去了
- We could burn our way in.
- Never.
- 我们可以把门溶掉闯进去  - 不能
- Why not?
- It's an X-structure alloy, you'd hardly scratch the surface.
- 为什么不能?  - 这是X结构合金, 你连表面都刮花不了
We'll have to try it. Get the gear up here. Fast!
我们必须得试试．把fixme拿过来．快！
Ha ha ha. Never get away with it?
Oh, that's good, coming from you.
哈哈哈．永远甩不掉？噢, 这太好了 fixme
Don't you realize you're dispensable,
你没发现你是可有可无的吗？
and the world is going to get along fine
without you from now on. /59.9
而且从今往后这个世界没有你也能运转得很好了
The only good idea you ever had in your life
was getting rid of me /03.2
你这一辈子唯一有过的好点子就是干掉我
and you couldn't even do that properly, could you?
Ha ha ha. And now I'm back and you're finished.
而你没有都没能实现, 是吗？哈哈哈, 现在我回来了, 而你完蛋了
Oh, what's that?
噢, 那是什么？
They're breaking down the door.
他们想把门破开
They don't appear to be having much success.
他们似乎没有什么进展
It's not cutting, sir.
切割不了, 长官
Never mind, keep at it.
别管, 继续
You're trapped, aren't you?
你被困住了, 对吧？
You're a fool, Salamander.
You don't think I'd forgotten already, do you?
你真傻, Salamander．你不会以为我已经忘记了吧, 是吗？
What?
什么？
I've been with you too many times in this room
in the past, not to know where this leads to.
以前我跟你在这个房间很多次, 也不知道这个东西通向哪里
Your little bolt-hole. Halfway down the tunnel. /42.2
A passage out to the fields...
你小小的藏匿之地, fixme 一条通道通向空地
and enough explosives down there
to stop you or your thugs following me.
那里有足够的炸药, 用来阻止你们这些跟在后面的家伙
Well that's very interesting Mister Kent.
Why didn't you tell me that before?
啊, 这很有意思 Kent 先生．你之前为什么不告诉我？
Oh no, it can't be.
噢, 不, 不可能
Oh, I'm afraid it is. Oh look.
Here's another surprise for you. Look behind you.
噢, 恐怕是的．噢, 看, 这里还有一个给你的惊喜, 看你后面
Astrid, you've come just in time.
Astrid, 你来的正是时候
It's too late, Giles, I know everything.
太迟了, Giles, 一切我都知道了
That's him, that's the man
who took us down there in the first place.
就是他, 一开始就是他把我们带去地底下的
Giles Kent, we thought you were dead.
Giles Kent, 我们以为你已经死了
Now look, I've never seen these people before in my life.
都听着, 我以前从来没见过这些人
They told me everything.
You and Salamander were in it together...
他们把一切都告诉我了．你和 Salamander 之前都在里面...
...You built an atomic shelter,
took some people down for an endurance test./?
你们建了一个原子弹掩体, 带了一些人下去做耐力测试
The next person they saw was Salamander...
他们看见的第二个人就是 Salamander...
...who told them that an atomic war had started.
...后者告诉他们核战争开始了
You see, Kent...
你看, Kent...
Oh, be careful, Doctor. He'll kill you.
噢, 小心点, 博士．他会杀死你的
You kept us down like animals.
你把我们像动物一样关在下面
Why? Why did you do it to us?
为什么？为什么要对我们这样？
We had to have someone create the natural disasters,
didn't we, and we fooled you all!
我们必须得有人来制造自然灾害, 对不, 而我们骗过了你们全部！
You didn't fool me, Kent...
你没有骗过我我, Kent...
You didn't suspect me.
你没有怀疑过我
Any man who resorts to murder as eagerly and as rapidly
as you must be suspect. /49.1
fixme
You didn't just want to expose Salamander,
you wanted to kill him and take his place.
你不想揭发 Salamander, 你只是想要杀死他取而代之
And I will! Think you're going to stop me?
And these people? /55.6
我会的！觉得你们能阻止我？就这些人？
Now move out of the way, quick!
We'll see who'll stop me!
现在都散开, 快！我们看看谁能阻止我！
Huh, he's going to try and blow the place up!
啊, 他要炸了这个地方！fixme
Come on then!
快点啊！
No! Don't touch that door, it's red hot.
不！别碰那个门, 都烧红了
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
Well it's locked.
They're trying to burn through from the other side.
噢它被锁住了．他们想把它从另外那边烧穿
Still no good, sir.
还是不行, 长官
Look! Salamander!
看！Salamander!
Yes. I wonder if he knows Kent's on his way?
是的．我在想他是否知道 Kent 在他的路上fixme
You always were a fool, weren't you?
你一直都是一个傻子, 对吧？
Now wait a minute. They'll be after both of us now.
现在等一下, 我们俩现在都会被他们追
Oh no they won't.
噢, 不, 他们不会的
I tell you, they know!
我告诉你, 他们知道！
So what you want me to do, huh?
Bury our differences, hmm? /45.0
所以你想让我做什么, 哈？尽弃前嫌, 嗯？fixme
I didn't need you once, I still don't need you.
我以前不需要你, 现在还是不需要你
Now wait a minute. The place is mined, we know that.
现在等等, 这个地方有地雷, 我们知道的
We planned it for years, together. /52.5
我们计划了好些年, 一起干的
Between us we can destroy them all, and the evidence.
Just you and me, Salamander.
我们一起可以把他们都消灭, 证据也可以消灭．就你和我, Salamander
You and me? What use are you to me?
You were useful once, but now...
你和我？你对我有什么用？你以前挺有用, 但现在...
No. No...
不, 不...
Ha ha ha ha. You won't get away from me, Kent. Ha ha ha ha.
哈哈哈哈, 你甩不掉我的, Kent．哈哈哈哈
Ha ha hah. I told you you could not escape me.
哈哈哈, 我告诉过你你逃不出我手心
Well if I'm going to die, Salamander, you'll die with me.
好, 如果我要死, Salamander．你也得跟我一起死
No! No!
不！不！
Aaaaaaa!
啊！
Come on Doctor, let's get out of here.
快点博士, 我们离开这里
Salamander, Giles, they're dead.
Salamander, Giles, 他们都死了
Come along man, quickly.
一起来伙计, 快点
The people...
那些人...
People. What people?
人？什么人？
The people underground in the deep shelter.
在地底掩体里面那些人
They may have been killed.
他们可能已经死了
I promised Swann I'd get them out.
我答应了 Swann 我会去把他们带出来的
But that's not your fault. You couldn't have done more.
但这不是你的错, 你已经做得够多了
There's a TV monitor screen in there.
There must be a link to the deep shelter.
这里面有个监视器, 那里肯定可以连通地底掩体
It's alright! They're alive!
没事了, 他们都活着！
How are you going to get to them?
你打算怎么去救他们呢？
There's a tunnel from outside.
We can get to it outside the Research Station.
外面有一条隧道．我们可以从研究站外面过去
But that's probably been destroyed by the explosion.
但它很可能被爆炸摧毁了
We'll get to them somehow.
不管怎样我们得去找他们
Lookout!
小心！
Get me some men. I'll lead them.
给我一些人, 我来带领他们
Alright. I'll go with you.
好吧, 我也跟你去
Oh good then. That's splendid. I'll come too.
哦, 那太好了．非常棒．我也去
Oh no Doctor. It's far too dangerous.
They might mistake you as Salamander.
噢, 不行博士, 太危险了．他们可能把你当作 Salamander
Oh yes. Ooooh.
噢是的, 噢
- Are you hurt?  - Oh I'm alright.
- 你受伤了？  - 哦我没事
I'll come with you as far as the gates.
Come along, we must go.
我陪你走到门口吧．都过来, 我们得走了
I thought you were never coming.
我以为你再也不会来了
Hey Doctor, are you alright?
嘿, 博士, 你没事吧？
Oh there you are Doctor. You do look in a state.
Come and sit down.
哦, 你在这里啊博士．你看起来不太好fixme, 过来坐下
I told you it wouldn't be long.
You, you worry too much.
我告诉过你不会太久了．你多虑了
We shouldn't have left him.
我们不应该离开他的
You see, after the explosion, Doctor,
we dinna know what to do./07.1
你看, 博士, 爆炸之后, 我们都不知道该怎么办了
You said to come back here, which we did,
but I'm sure we were followed.
你说过要回这里来, 我们照做了, 但我不确定我们是否被跟踪了
Please, can we start straight away?
摆脱, 我们能直接开始了不？fixme
Me, Doctor? But you said we were never to touch the controls.
我吗, 博士？但你说过我们永远不要碰那些开关
Quite right, Jamie. Welcome to the TARDIS.
没事的, Jamie．欢迎来到 TARDIS
Thank you. You're doing so well impersonating me, ah,
I thought I might return the compliment.
谢谢你, 你冒充我冒充得很好, 啊, 我以为你会回赞我一下
And Giles Kent?
Giles Kent 呢？
Unfortunately, didn't survive the explosion.
很不幸, 没能在爆炸中幸存下来
We're going to put you outside, Salamander,
no friends, no safety, nothing. /49.5
我们打算放你出去, Salamander, 没有朋友, 没有安全, 什么都没有
You'll run, but they'll catch up with you.
你可以跑, 但他们会追上你的
No!
不！
And now I'm going to kill you.
而现在我要杀了你
No you don't.
不, 你不能
Oh, Doctor!
噢, 博士！
Victoria! Jamie! Hold onto something!
Victoria! Jamie! 抓牢什么东西!
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaa!
啊----！
Jamie! Oh!
Jamie! 噢！
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaa!
啊----!